Miss Americana is a documentary, music film directed by Lana Wilson.
A raw and emotionally revealing look at one of the most iconic artists of our time during a transformational period in her life as she
learns to embrace her role not only as a songwriter and performer, but as a woman harnessing the full power of her voice.
Self, played by Taylor Swift.
Self, played by Todrick Hall.
Self, played by Brendon Urie.
Self, played by Jack Antonoff.
Self, played by Bobby Berk.
Self, played by Jonathan Van Ness.
Miss Americana (also known as Taylor Swift: Miss Americana) is a 2020 American documentary film that follows
the singer-songwriter Taylor Swift and her life over the course of several years of her career.
It was directed by Lana Wilson, produced by Tremolo Productions, and
released to Netflix and select theaters on January 31, 2020.
The film is titled after "Miss Americana & the
Heartbreak Prince", a 2019 song by Swift.
The film has been described as an unvarnished and emotionally revealing look at Swift, during a metamorphic phase in her life, as she learns to accept her role as not only a singer-songwriter and entertainer, but as an influential woman "harnessing the full power of her
voice." It is set in the time period spanning from Swift's Reputation Stadium Tour (2018) to the release roll-out of her seventh studio album, Lover (2019), dotted with flashback video clips portraying several undisclosed events of her life and career.
Premiering at the opening night of 2020 Sundance Film Festival on January 23, 2020, Miss
Americana was praised for its emotion, intimacy, and vulnerable topics.
Reviews complimented Swift's honesty and personality.
Accompanying the film's release, "Only the Young", a song by Swift featured
in the end credits, was released as a promotional single.
Miss Americana was selected by the National Board of Review as
one of the five best documentaries of 2020.
Publications have named it amongst the best Netflix films and biographical
documentaries and regard it a pivotal moment for Swift's career.
The film explores themes of politics, pop star, pop
culture, behind the scenes, pop music.
The tone is emotional.